コードギアス反逆のルルーシュR2 TURN 20　皇帝　失格
TURN 20　皇帝　失格
2010 of the Imperial Calendar.
皇歴2010年　日本は地下資源サクラダイトの扱いをめぐり
Japan entered a state of war with the Holy
Britannian Empire and was invaded...
for control of its underground
sakuradite resources.
神聖ブリタニア帝国と戦争状態に突入した
徹底抗戦をとなえた父　ゲンブに対し 僕は
To stop my father Genbu, who
called for a do-or-die resistance, I!
幼い あまりにも幼い衝動的な行為
It was childish.
A far too childish, impulsive act.
しかし これで戦争は終わると　僕は思った
But I thought "this will end the war."
I thought that there wouldn't be
any more needless bloodshed.
無駄な血が流れることは　もうないのだと
なのに  戦いは終わらなかった
But, despite that, the fighting didn't end.
僕はただ　人が人を殺めるということをとめたかっただけなのに
All I wanted was to stop people killing each other.
違う！これは違う！ギアスが 人の意志を捻じ曲げる力が
No! No! It was the Geass!
The power that twists peoples' will!
イヤ 結局同じだ俺が
No... In the end,
it's just the same.
I!
I... I didn't understand.
私 わからなくって
That it would be this awful.
こんなひどいことになるなんて
あの あたしが こんな こんなに
That I... That I would...
殺した
Kill so many?
大成功だよ　ニーナ
It's a great success, Nina.
The F.L.E.I.J.A. warhead has immense power.
フレイヤ弾頭の威力は絶大だ
It will ensure Britannia's victory.
結果的に　我がブリタニアに勝利をもたらすだろう
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
Kireigoto dake jaa ikirenai
Pretty words alone won't sustain you
Yasashisa dake jaa iyasenai
Kindness alone won't heal you
Ubawareta nowa nanda
What is it that was stolen from you
Kawaranai sekai de
In this unchanging world
Kikoetekita nowa nanda
What is it that you hear
Shikisai no uta
A song of color
Everything is bright...
Kudakechitta yume wo
Let our crumbled dreams resound
Asu no hate ni hibikaseru you ni
At the edge of tomorrow
Sekai no owari de
At the end of the world
Umareta hikari
The light that's born
Bokura hitotsu ni
Becomes one with us
Ima kaze no naka
Now blows in the wind
EMPEROR DISMISSED
エリア11にきていながら
Even though he was headed for Area 11,
皇帝はトウキョウ租界にあらわれなかった
the emperor never showed up
in the Tokyo Settlement.
つまり あいつの目的は別にある
Which means he had
another objective.
方角的には式根島 いや神根島の遺跡か？
His heading was taking him in the
direction of Shikine Island... No!
The ruins on Kamine Island?!
嚮主V.V.と我らの同志が残した資料によると
According to the materials left behind by Director
V.V. and our brethren, this point is optimal.
このポイントが最適です
世界中に散らばる遺跡も同期させます
It will synchronize with the rest of the
ruins scattered throughout the world.
これでアーカーシャの剣は 再び使用可能になるでしょう
With this, we can make the Sword
of Akasha usable once again.
ふっ
こんな古の装置をつかうことになるとはなあ
To think that I could use
such an ancient device.
そう　はじめるつもりなのね
I see... You're ready to begin, aren't you?
蜃気楼の現在位置は？！
What's the Shinkirō's current location?!
それが いまだ
Well, Lord... We don't know yet.
くっブリタニアの協力も得られている
We have the Britannians assisting us as well!
確認しだい全軍をあげて蜃気楼を破壊するんだ
As soon as you confirm its location,
alert all forces and destroy it!
わかりました
Yes, sir!
御主人さまは
What about my master?
はっ
It's been ages since we were
face to face like this!
直接あうなんて久しぶりね
私よ 私ん？
It's me! It's me!
C.C.まさかあなた
C.C., don't tell me you've...
ごめんなさい！
Forgive me!
何やってるの？
What are you doing,
closing yourself up in here again?
またこんなところにとじこもって
C.C.？C.C.
C.C.? C.C.!
ん？誰だ？
Who are you?
私よ 私ほら
It's me. See?
You! So, you've chased me
all the way in here, now?
おまえ こんなところまでやってきて
そんなにルルーシュが心配か？マリアンヌ
Are you that worried
about Lelouch, Marianne?
あら私がそんなに理想的な母親だと思っていたの？
Oh, please! Do you really think
I'm that ideal a mother?
では どうしてここに？
Then why did you come here?
あなたが今でも私たちの味方なのか知りたくって
Because I wanted to know
if you're still on my side.
え？
C.C.自分のコードを自分で封印したのはなぜ？
C.C., why did you seal off
your own Code?
シャルルなら あなたの願いを 死にたいという思いをかなえてくれたのに
Even when Charles would have
granted your wish to die.
わからないんだよ 自分でも
Even I don't know why I did it.
I'm a little shocked that I did.
ちょっと驚いている
あはははは
じゃ確かめなきゃね現実で
Well, then you have to find
out for sure, in the real world.
Well...
私が決めたんだから決定よ
I've decided,
and that's all there is to it.
おまえくらいだな
How typical of you.
何が？
What is?
The way you always come in
and mess around with me.
この私をいつもひっかきまわそうとするのは
ああ感謝はしてるよ
Yes, because I appreciate
what you did.
私にギアスをくれたことに対しては
At least as far as
giving me my Geass.
契約不履行のくせに
Says the woman who never
fulfilled her contract.
If you think that,
shall you come with me?
そう思うのならいっしょにいきましょう
ああ 待ってくれ
Right, but hold on a moment.
There's something I need to take.
せめてあれだけは
ん？
このイカルガにはアーニャを残していく
I'm having Anya remain here
aboard the Ikaruga.
ゼロの身柄を引き取るものが必要だからな
We'll need someone here
to take custody of Zero.
で おまえはこれからどうする？
And now, what do you plan to do?
Stay with the Black Knights?
黒の騎士団に残るのか？
兄上も私もここでおまえを罰するつもりはない
Neither my brother nor myself
plan to punish you here.
いや 状況が次の段階に入ったため
No, now that the situation has
advanced to the next level,
手がだせなくなったというべきかな
there's no way we can act against you now.
その 私は
Well... I...
私がいうのもなんだが 世の中は爵位だけではないぞ
I'm probably the last person
who should say this,
but noble rank isn't
everything in this world.
しかたないゼロの戦死を発表しましょう
We have no choice.
Let's announce that
Zero was killed in battle.
まだルルーシュがみつかっていないのに？
Even though we haven't
found Lelouch yet?
既成事実にしようというのか？
You want people to
think that he's dead?
あのさあゼロが裏切っていたってのはわかったんだけど
Excuse me. I understand that
Zero has betrayed us and all that,
ギアスのことも発表するつもり？
but will you tell people about
that Geass power of his, too?
私たちがおかしくなったと思われ放逐されるだけです
That would just get us thrown out as a
bunch of madmen! There's no way we can!
ありえない
本物のゼロがでてきたら？
And what if the real Zero appears later?
本物だとどうやって証明するのですか
And how exactly would he
prove that he's the real Zero?
仮面の英雄などしょせんは記号
In the end, a masked hero
is merely a symbol.
認めるものがいなければ成り立ちません
If no one acknowledges him,
he will never establish himself.
そうか それはよかった本当に
Really?
That's great news! Really.
ああ やっと携帯がつながるようになったからさ
Yeah! They finally got the
cell phones working again...
みんな無事だってわかったよ
and we found out
everyone was okay!
ああ そうそう お前達の部屋はなくなっちゃったけど
Oh, yeah. Your room was destroyed,
but there's room in the clubhouse.
クラブハウスはあいてるよ
そうか生徒会室は無事か？
I see. Is the student
council room okay?
うんああ そういえばロロは？
Yeah. By the way, where's Rolo?
Is he with you?
いっしょなんだろ？
あ ああ
Y-Yeah...
リヴァル 会長に伝えてくれないか？
Rivalz...
Can you tell the Prez
something for me?
一緒に花火をする約束 守れそうにないって
Tell her I won't be able to keep my
promise to shoot off fireworks with you all.
What was that supposed to mean?
何言ってんだ？あいつ
リヴァル すまない
Rivalz... I'm sorry.
カレンC.C.のことはたのむ
Kallen, take care of C.C.
俺は刺し違えてでも　あの男を倒す
Even if I die doing it,
I have to defeat that man!
不老不死 ギアスのきかないあの男を倒す賭けにでる
I'm gambling that I can defeat an unaging
immortal who is immune to the power of Geass.
もうそれしか 俺には
That's all I have left now!
陛下　同調準備 完了いたしました
Your Majesty, we've completed
preparations for synchronization.
Very well.
Let us begin, then.
ようし始めよ
なんか揺れてない？
I feel something shaking.
そうか？
You do?
各遺跡システム　同調完了しました
All relic systems
are now synchronized.
これで既存の神の世界は終わる
With this shall end the world
of the existing God.
破壊と創造　ラグナレクがはじまる
Destruction and creation...
Ragnarok begins!
陛下トウキョウ租界のシュナイゼル殿下より通信が
Your Majesty, I have a communication from
Prince Schneizel in the Tokyo Settlement...
まかせるといったはず俗事など
Did I not tell you to leave
these mundane affairs to him?
俗事？
Mundane?
シュナイゼルめさて気づきおったか
Damn you, Schneizel.
Has the truth begun to dawn on you?
だがもうおそい
Even so, it's too late!
This game called war is already obsolete.
戦争という名のゲームはおしまい よ
こちらはＫＴテレビです
This is KTTV.
スタジオがなくなってしまったため
As we've lost our studios, we've set up
a temporary one at Ashford Academy...
ここアッシュフォード学園臨時スタジオより
to bring you this
emergency news flash.
緊急速報をお伝えします
先ほどシュナイゼル殿下は 黒の騎士団と停戦条約を結んだと
A short while ago,
we received official word...
that Prince Schneizel has signed a
cease-fire with the Black Knights.
公式に発表しました
また 黒の騎士団からは
In addition,
it's been reported that Zero,
CEO　ゼロの死亡が発表されています
the CEO of the Black Knights,
was killed in battle.
ゼロはトウキョウ租界での戦闘で負傷し
Zero was wounded in the battle
for the Tokyo Settlement...
旗艦イカルガ内で治療をうけていましたが
KAGOSHIMA SETTLEMENT COAST
and was treated aboard
the flagship Ikaruga,
本日未明 艦内で息をひきとったとのことです
but succumbed to his
injuries early this morning.
ゼロ様～そんな
United States of Japan
Provisional Capital - HORAI ISLAND
うそだ
- Master Zero!
- It can't be!
It can't be true!
どういうことだ 扇
What's the meaning of this, Ohgi?
Is it true that Zero is dead?!
ゼロが死亡したとはまことなのか？
ああ残念ながら公式発表のとおりだ
Yeah. I'm afraid it's just as
the public announcement says.
では せめてお顔だけでも
Could I at least see his face?
すまない今は何かと立て込んでいて
Sorry, but we're busy right now.
It'll have to wait till later.
この件はあとで
本気なんですか？
Are you serious about this?
黒の騎士団に もうゼロは必要ない
The Black Knights
don't need Zero anymore!
We've only gotten
this far because of Zero!
私たち ゼロのおかげでここまでやってきたのに
こんな　使い捨てるような
To just throw him
away like this is!
彼はみんなを使い捨てたのはゼロのほうだ
He was the one who treated us
like we were disposable!
彼はみんなをだましていたんだ
He fooled us all!
ギアスなんて卑劣な力で
With that despicable
Geass power of his!
俺だってさ 親友だと思っていたんだよ
I even considered
the guy my best friend.
好きだったんだあいつのことが！
I loved that guy, dammit!
でも あいつは ブラックリベリオンのときも扇を使い捨てにしようとして
But...
He was ready to cut Ohgi loose
back during the Black Rebellion.
いや それ以前からも
No. Even before that.
そうだ
That's right. People...
They aren't just game pieces to play with!
人は　みんなはゲームの駒じゃないんだ
生きているんだよ
They're living beings!
ルルーシュ ヴィ ブリタニアが命じる
Lelouch vi Britannia commands you!
おまえたちは 今より
From this moment forward,
you shall obey my orders!
私の指示どおりにに動け
あっ 手ごわい
Damn, she's good!
ロイドさん ランスロットはどうなっていますか？
Lloyd, what's the status of the Lancelot?
どうってコアルミナスがあの状態じゃ
What about it? You saw
the condition of the core luminous.
いえランスロット アルビオンのほうです
No, I meant the Lancelot Albion.
ロールアウト直前
It's just about to be rolled out.
なんだい？アルビオンって
So, what's this Albion thing?
ああ 枢木スザク専用に開発したナイトメアなんだけど
It's a custom Knightmare
built for Suzaku Kururugi.
今の君にはわたしたくないね
I don't want to hand it over
to you the way you are now.
これは命令ですナイトオブセブンとしての
This is an order,
as the Knight of Seven.
ますますいやになったよ
My unease grows worse and worse.
スザクくん あなたは フレイヤを撃たない覚悟も必要だと言っていたわね
Suzaku, didn't you say you had to be
prepared to not fire the F.L.E.I.J.A.?
セシルさん
Miss Cécile, what is a weapon in the first place?
兵器とはそもそもなんでしょう
枢木卿 子どもの議論をするつもり？
Sir Kururugi, do you want
to have a childish debate now?
自分は
I...
やめておけよスザクらしくないだろ
Stop it, Suzaku. This isn't like you.
ああ　これは
Oh! Your Highness!
いいよ そのままで
It's all right. At ease.
お久しぶりですコーネリア皇女殿下！
Princess Cornelia! It's been
far too long, Your Highness!
ああギルフォードはどうした？
Right...
Where's Guilford?
あっ その
Um, well...
コーネリア実はギルフォード卿は
Cornelia, the truth is, Guilford was...
今回の戦闘で フレイヤ弾頭による攻撃を仕掛けたものの行方知れずに
I'm afraid he went missing after
he fired the F.L.E.I.J.A. warhead.
ギルフォードが？
Guilford?!
生死不明とはいえ 功績は大きい
We may not know if he's alive or dead,
but he did a great deed.
誇っていいよさすがは コーネリアの騎士だ
You should be proud of him.
He served you well as your knight.
待ってください
Wait, please! I was the one
who fired the F.L.E.I.J.A. warhead.
フレイヤ弾頭を撃ったのは自分です
えっ
あれは自分の功績です
That was my deed! One I needed
to do to become the Knight of One!
ナイトオブワンになるために必要な
おい スザクとジノ
Whoa, Suzaku!
この処置は
Is this manipulation designed to
protect Lord Guilford's honor?
ギルフォード卿の名誉を守るためですか？
何を言っている？
What are you saying?
よしたまえ スザクくん
I suggest you stop, Suzaku.
いいえ これまでの自分は甘かった
No. I've been naive up till now.
あっそ
Have you now?
結果より手段といいながら
I was being idealistic and
sanctimonious by always saying...
自分が大事にしていたのは
that the means were more
important than the ends.
理想や美学だったのではないかと
しかし
But...
それとも 殿下がしていただけるんですか？
In any case, will you do it, Your Highness?
Make me the Knight of One?
自分をナイトオブワンに
あまりにも不敬な発言だな枢木
That demand crosses the line
into lèse majesté , Kururugi!
ナイトオブワンの任命は
Only His Majesty can name somebody
the Knight of One. Which means...
皇帝陛下にしかできないんだよつまり
では　なるとしよう
All right, then I'll become one.
え？は？兄上
Brother!
私が皇帝になるよ
I shall become the emperor.
That will remove the problem, won't it?
それなら問題はないだろう
殿下 その発言は
Highness, what you said just now is...
ジノ
Gino.
どういうつもりだ これは
What are you planning to do?!
シュナイゼル殿下今のお言葉は本気ですか
Prince Schneizel, were you serious
about what you said just now?
俗事と おっしゃったそうだよ
I heard he called it mundane.
陛下は 黒の騎士団との戦争のことを
That's what His Majesty referred to
the war with the Black Knights as.
しかし
But!
コーネリアも知っているだろう？
You know it as well,
Cornelia, don't you?
父上は 危険な研究にのめりこみ
How absorbed Father is with his dangerous
research and how he frequently leaves the throne.
たびたび玉座を離れた
そう 政治を 戦争をゲームとして扱ったんだよ
Yes. He treats politics
and war like a game.
この世界に今日と言う日に興味を失い
A man who's lost interest in the
here and now in this world...
みんなが苦しんでいるのをただ眺めているだけの男に
and just ignores all the people
who suffer has no right to be king!
王たる資格はない
やっとご決断なされたわ
He's finally made up his mind. But...
でも
これって　クーデター？
Um... Is this a coup d'état
I'm witnessing?
そんな
No...
陛下ラウンズの自分なら
Your Highness, as one of the Rounds,
I can arrange an audience with the emperor.
陛下に謁見がかないます
自分に　皇帝陛下暗殺をお命じください
Please give me the order
to assassinate him.
スザク！
Suzaku!
人を殺めるというのが自分の業ならば
If my destiny is to be a killer, then...
ジノ僕はこれを認めよう
Gino, I acknowledge this truth.
必要なものは 結果だ
What's most necessary are results!
では　天子様打ち合わせ通り
Now then, Your Majesty,
as we previously arranged,
トウキョウでは 私がシュナイゼル宰相と交渉を行います
I'll conduct negotiations with
Prime Minister Schneizel in Tokyo.
神楽耶その ゼロのことは
Kaguya...
Look, about Zero...
ゼロ様を失ったのは たいへんな痛手です
Losing Master Zero is a terrible blow.
ゆえに 私たちは彼の死を 最大限有効に活用せねばなりません
Therefore, we have to turn his death
to our best advantage.
それに 夫といってもゼロ様と私は
Besides, I know I called myself his wife,
but he and I were just...
しょ しょせん　形だけの 夫婦で
In... In the end,
we were only married in form.
皇帝陛下が 神根島に上陸された？
His Majesty has landed
on Kamine Island?
はい所属不明の方々と共に
Yes, my lord, along with
an unknown group of people.
所属不明ギアス嚮団の生き残りか？
Unknown people...
Survivors of the Geass Order?
本気でスザクに皇帝陛下を暗殺させるおつもりですか？
You're serious about sending
Suzaku to kill the emperor?!
ジノ君は　今のままでいいというのかい？
Gino, do you want things
to remain as they are now?
それは
Well...
人の本質とはね
The true nature of people
is that they want to be controlled.
何かに支配されたいということなんだよ
民族　宗教　伝統　権威
By ethnicity, by religion,
by tradition, by authority.
ブリタニア皇帝はそれらを演じねばならない
The emperor of Britannia
must play his part.
殿下なら 演じられるというのですか？権威を
And you're the one to play the
part of authority, Your Highness?
それが求められているなら たぶん
If I am called to play it, then perhaps.
あっ たぶん　とは？
Perhaps... Meaning?
権威のもう一つの意味を知っているかい？
Did you know that authority
has another meaning?
シュナイゼルの　さしがねか
Was this Schneizel's idea?
自分の意思です
It's my decision. Majesty, I appreciate
the patronage you provided me.
陛下自分をとりたてていただいたことには感謝しています
しかし あなたには二つの罪がある
But you're guilty of two crimes!
ほ～う
Am I?
一つは 王たる責務を放棄したこと
First, abandoning your
responsibilities as king.
そしてもうひとつに
And second...
ギアスに手を染めたこと
dirtying your hands with
the power of Geass!
それが罪だと？
Is that a crime?
ギアスは 人の悪なるものをひきだします
Geass brings out
the evil nature in people.
そうすべてを知るあなたなら
Yes. If you knew about everything,
then you could have saved Euphy.
ユフィのことだって救えたはず
なのに見捨てた
But you abandoned her!
それがどうした？
So what?
くっこの剣に ルルーシュとナナリーの絶望もこめさせていただきます
Into this sword, I put the despair
you drove Lelouch and Nunnally to!
覚悟！
Prepare to die!
ヴァルトシュタイン卿どうしてここに？
Lord Waldstein!
Why are you here?!
ギアスの事を知っているのは自分だけだと思っていたか？
Did you think you were the only
one who knew about Geass?
残念だったな
A pity. Who would have trusted a man
like you who constantly betrays people?
おまえのような裏切り続けの男を 誰が信じるというのか
ビスマルク　俗事はまかせる
Bismarck, I leave this
mundane matter to you.
イエス　ユアマジェスティ
Yes, Your Majesty.
待て！
Wait!
扇かホン グだ着艦許可を頼みたい
Ohgi? This is Hong Gu.
Requesting landing clearance.
天子様と 神楽耶様をおつれした
We've brought Her Majesty
and Lady Kaguya with us.
あ ああ
R-Right. Then I'll contact
Schneizel's people as well.
じゃあ シュナイゼルの方にも連絡をとるから
扇も少しはかわったかと思ったが
And here I thought
Ohgi had changed a bit.
やはりミスキャストか
Definitely miscast.
彼の本質は 守ることにある
His true nature is to be defensive.
いけない
Uh-oh. The Geass spell
that compels me to live.
僕にかかっている生きろというギアスが
ここは逃げろと叫んでいる
It's screaming at me to run away!
それほどまでに危険な相手か
Is the Knight of One really
that dangerous an opponent?!
ナイトオブワン！
しかし！弱さは捨てた！
Even so, I've left
my weakness behind!
愚かな おまえの弱さこそが！
Fool! Your weakness...
優しさという強さの裏付けであったものを
is what supported the strength you
possessed, which was gentleness!
そう規範なき強さなどただの暴力
That's right. Strength without a standard to
follow is merely violence. Which means...
ならば　ここで死ぬがよい枢木スザク
You should die here,
Suzaku Kururugi!
我が名はルルーシュ ヴィ ブリタニア
My name is Lelouch vi Britannia!
マリアンヌ皇妃が長子にして
Eldest son of Empress Marianne!
帝国により捨てられし皇子
The prince who was
abandoned by his empire!
皇帝陛下と連絡がつかない
We can't contact His Majesty!
不審者は捕縛ではなく　殺害を前提に対処せよ！
You are to kill, not capture,
any suspicious people you find!
イエス　マイロード
Yes, My Lord!
な なに？なぜ我らを？うわっ
Wh-What the hell?!
Why are you shooting at us?!
どうして味方を撃っているの？！
Why are we shooting
at our own people?!
確認中ですが 第三砲塔室と連絡がとれません
We're still verifying it,
but we can't contact gun turret room 3!
何ものかに占拠された可能性が
It's possible someone's
taken it over!
応答せよ第三砲塔室
Respond! Turret room 3!
If you do not respond, we'll remove you by force!
応答なき場合は 強制的に排除する
我らロイヤルガードに続け！
Follow us in the royal guard!
Destroy all enemies!
敵はすべて排除する
Yes, My Lord!
イエス　マイロード
あっ
式根島基地からの援軍がすべて敵対行動をとっています！
All the reinforcements from the
Shikine Island base are attacking us!
わが陣営内でも　同志討ちが報告されていますが
We're getting reports of people in
our own ranks turning on us as well!
これは
This is...
反乱だと？！
A rebellion?!
はい皇帝陛下は？
Yes, My Lord!
Where is His Majesty?
陛下はもっとも安全なところにうつっておられる
His Majesty is in the safest
place he could be. For now, we...
今は ん？
ルルーシュそれは僕の十字架だ
Lelouch!
That's my cross to bear!
グレートオブリタニアで指揮をとっているのは？
Who has command aboard
the Great Britannia?!
ナイトオブトゥエルブ　モニカ クルシェフスキー卿です
Lady Monica Krushevsky,
the Knight of Twelve.
よしならば私はギャラハッドででる！
Very well!
Then I'll go out in the Galahad!
モルドレッドとはまだ連絡がつかないの？
You still can't contact the Mordred?
はい目的地は神根島かと
No, My Lord, although I think
she's headed for Kamine Island.
とすると 先ほどの情報をうけて皇帝陛下のところに移動したのかな
Meaning she just received that
intelligence and is going to His Majesty?
スザクくんとともに いや これは
Along with Suzaku? No, this is...
神楽耶さま申し訳ありません
My apologies, Lady Kaguya.
これから神根島にむかわなければなりませんので
We have to get to Kamine Island at once.
では 私たちもまいります
Then we shall go with you, as well.
この状況下で
There's only one
person I can think of...
ブリタニア皇帝に刃を向ける人物に
who would be attacking the
Britannian emperor in this situation.
私は1人しか心当たりがありません
私も同じです
I agree.
とすると 確認すべき点がいくつかありそうです
Which means we have
a few points to verify.
会談の続きはこの件がすんでからといたしましょう
We can continue this meeting
once this matter is settled.
止められるものなら止めてみよ
If anyone wishes to stop me,
let them try!
我が絶望に　かなうものがいるのなら
If there are any whose despair
can match my own!
敵が誰なのかさだかではないが
I can't tell friend from foe,
but I also can't just destroy them all.
すべてを破壊するわけにもいかぬし ん？
アーニャ！まさかおまえまで！
Anya! Surely you aren't
part of this, too!
クーデターにくみするとは
So, the Knight of One
is behind this coup d'état?!
それでもナイトオブワンか？
なに？
What?!
ふははは ふはははははっ！
勘違いするな！
Don't jump to conclusions!
How can I trust you?!
どうやって信じろと？
敵は式根島からきたモニカも証言してくれる
The enemy is from Shikine Island!
Monica can testify to it!
わかりましたもうしわけありません
Understood. Forgive me.
理解したならそれでいい
All I ask is for you to understand that.
How damaged are you?
機体の損傷は？
空戦機動力が低下しています
My air combat mobility is dropping.
陸上から反乱軍を迎え撃とうとおもいますが
I was thinking I could intercept
the rebel forces on the ground.
わかった私は御座艦を守ろう
Understood.
I'll defend the royal flagship.
たいした役者だな
Quite the actress, aren't you?
ビスマルクに説明している時間はないから
We don't have time
to explain things to Bismarck.
こちらから疑っちゃえば
If you start off suspecting someone,
it keeps them from mistrusting you, right?
向こうは疑わないでしょう
そのひらめき おとろえてはいないようだな
The sort of flash I'd expect
from Marianne the Flash.
閃光のマリアンヌ
さすがはルルーシュの母親だ
Just what I expect
from Lelouch's mother.
ねえ どうしよう
Now what?
ん？
助けるべきかな 彼を
We have to save him, don't we?
さあ　神よ
Now then, God!
決着の時はきた
The time has come to settle this!
違うな
Wrong.
間違っているぞ
You're mistaken, Charles zi Britannia.
シャルル ジ ブリタニア
決着をつけるべきは神ではない
It's not God you need
to settle things with.
この　俺だ！
It's with me!
どのようにして？
And how do you plan to do that?
銃でも剣でもギアスでも
Neither gun, nor sword,
nor Geass will work.
わしを殺すことはできぬというのに
I have told you already
that you cannot kill me!
感謝する
I'm thankful.
貴様がこの場所に入ってくれたおかげで
By coming in here,
you've ensured my victory.
勝利の目算が立った
ん
くっ
出口を封じた？！
You've sealed the exit?!
そうだギアスも貴様も
Yes.
You, I, and the power of Geass are
now sealed in this space together.
俺とともにこの空間に閉じ込める
現実世界に干渉できなくなれば
If you cannot interfere
with the real world,
貴様が何をたくらんでいようと意味をなさない
then whatever you're up to
will be meaningless in the end.
死んだも同然だ
You may as well be dead!
ルル～シュ！
Lelouch!
貴様がつくったこのシステムが
This system you've made has become a prison
which now holds your own soul captive!
今貴様自身を閉じ込める　魂の牢獄となった
さあ 俺とともに
Now, let us repent!
Suffering together for all eternity!
永遠の懺悔に苦しむがいい！
Dakuse wa oni
This corrupt world is filled with demons
Seigi wa nanzo to
What is justice?
Tou mae ni aragae yo
Resist, don't just question
Akutoku no hana
The flower of evil
Gizen no yume
Dreams of hypocrisy
Mishi me niwa me wo sashi
Give your gaze to the eyes that see them
Sei mo ja mo wakatareru koto nashi
The line between right and wrong cannot be known
Hikari wa tae taiji no you ni
Light is gone, and you slumber
Kimi wa nemuru yami no shikyuu
Like an unborn child in the womb of darkness
Kodoku koso itooshii
Isolation is what you love
Yui-itsu no mikata to naru darou
It will probably be your only ally
Hitori hitori chishio ni mamire
One by one, stained with the tide of blood
Kono jidai ni umare ochita
You were born into this era
Erabareshi oujira yo
Oh, chosen princes
Tatakai koso shukuen
Battle shall be your banquet
Aa ware wa uruwashii zenchi
Oh, I am graceful omniscience
Ai no haha
The loving mother
Kimi wo umu
Who bore you
Kono chichi ni hagukumishi mono wa
The ones who were raised on my breast
Jigoku no harakara
Are your brethren in hell
Mokushi no in
The mark of apocalypse
Shinri wa nanzo to
What is truth
Shirimosezu uzumoreshi intoku no tane
A seed of secrecy buried where no one knows
Moroha no ken
A double-edged sword
Nuku ha niwa ha wo muke
Turn its blade upon the unsheathed blade
Mamorubeki mono dake wo shinjite
Believe only in what you must protect
Aru ga mama ni kimi wa
And in your own way
Kimi wo hanate
You'll set yourself free
今さらあとには下がれない
Now I see. Perhaps I did choose the wrong path.
そう俺は向き合おう　俺が俺であるためのすべてを賭けてこの男と
Perhaps Suzaku was right all along.
ブリタニア皇帝シャルルと
It's the means that are important.
But I can't back down now!
その先にたとえ何が待っていようと
For Euphy and Shirley,
Nunnally and Rolo.
俺は
That's right!
I must face him!
ルルーシュだ
今週も楽しんでくれてありがとう
I have to wager everything
I am against this man!
いつも応援してくれているみんなにご覧のプレゼントを送る
Charles, the emperor of Britannia!
パスワードを入力してこちらのケータイサイトから応募してほしい
No matter what awaits me
in the end, I must win!
今から一時間限定の受付だ
THE RAGNAROK CONNECTION
もちろん　特製待受けもあるぞ
それでは諸君　来週もお楽しみに